<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Harpurs Hill</title>
    <description>Harpurs Hill</description>
    <link/>
    <pubDate>2014-03-25</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Little Rays</title>
      <link>/harpurs/activities/little-rays</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Little Rays &#x2013; Sure Start Two to Three Year Old Development Programme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sure Start programme for two to three year olds is an exciting programme where the emphasis is on play and creativity.  We offer a variety of opportunities not only to young children but also to their parents and carers by actively involving them in the programme, thus helping to create strong relationships within our Centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criteria for this programme specifically targeted at two year olds  living in the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine Creche</title>
      <link>/harpurs/activities/creche</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Sunshine Creche&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our creche is a great stepping stone for children progressing onto other types of childcare services.  The creche gives the children the opportunity to play and interact with other children their own age and helps build confidence and socialising skills.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="creche-sessions"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Wednesday &amp;amp; Thursday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Birth to 1 year&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1 to 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: &lt;a href="contact#karen"&gt;Karen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine Playgroup</title>
      <link>/harpurs/activities/playgroup</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Sunshine Playgroup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the children start Sunshine Playgroup, we recognise that they have already had a variety of experiences and have developed in a number of ways.  We will endeavour to build upon the learning that has taken place in the home and their immediate environment as well as previous play experiences.  Therefore the staff team will provide children with a rich variety of challenging play activities and other experiences in a stimulating environment.  The focus will be to allow children to learn at their own pace, gain a positive image of themselves as learners, be able to cope with uncertainty and to learn through trial and error.  The staff team use the &#x2018;Preschool Curricular Guidance&#x2019; document as laid down by the Department of Education to influence their planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="playgroup-sessions"&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Monday to Friday&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;9.15am to 11.45am&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;3+ years&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
