<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Harpurs Hill</title>
    <description>Harpurs Hill</description>
    <link/>
    <pubDate>2014-03-12</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>About us</title>
      <link>/harpurs/about</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;About us&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project was established in 1993 to address low levels of preparedness for school.
It takes a holistic approach combining community development with delivering 
people-centred, family support services.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project runs an &lt;a href="/harpurs/childcare"&gt;Early Years programme&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="/harpurs/families"&gt;home visiting service&lt;/a&gt; and a range of personal development programmes and &lt;a href="/harpurs/groups"&gt;activities for adults&lt;/a&gt;.  It also encourages parents to become involved in running the Project.  The Project also shares the building with the Cuilrath Corner Nursery School which is run by the Education Service.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1999 the Project has become one of the main players in the delivery of Children&amp;#39;s Services in the Coleraine Area and in 2003 it became the lead body of the Coleraine Sure Start Partnership.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project is managed by a Board representing a range of stakeholders and is a company limited by guarantee.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aims</title>
      <link>/harpurs/aims</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Our Aims and Objectives&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&#x201C;Nurturing children......Strengthening families......Growing community&#x201D;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#x201C;To nurture strong, resilient children and families for today, tomorrow and the future&#x201D;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#x201C;We endeavour to support, strengthen and nurture children and families to achieve their full potential&#x201D;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To nurture young children from birth through the provision of high quality care and learning environments and to ensure they reach their full potential.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To recognise and support parents in their role as primary educators of their children through home support, parenting programmes and offering high quality care and learning environments.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To empower parents to seek appropriate advice and guidance to support their families developmental needs.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To signpost parents to opportunities for personal and professional development.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To provide parents with access to information to make informed life choices.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To develop an increased sense of ownership and belonging for families within their own community.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To work in partnership with all relevant children and family support agencies.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_4"&gt;Value base&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empowerment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family Friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Childcare</title>
      <link>/harpurs/childcare</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Childcare Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the aim of the childcare services within Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre to provide a quality service where you and your child will feel welcomed and valued within safe and secure environment.  We provide a variety of activities for various ages and stages of development, where children can develop and grow under to guidance of a professional, caring and fully qualified staff team.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Sunshine Creche&lt;a name=early-years&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our creche is a great stepping stone for children progressing onto other types of childcare services.  The creche gives the children the opportunity to play and interact with other children their own age and helps build confidence and socialising skills.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="creche-sessions"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Wednesday &amp;amp; Thursday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Birth to 1 year&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1 to 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Little Rays &#x2013; Sure Start Two to Three Year Old Development Programme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sure Start programme for two to three year olds is an exciting programme where the emphasis is on play and creativity.  We offer a variety of opportunities not only to young children but also to their parents and carers by actively involving them in the programme, thus helping to create strong relationships within our Centre.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criteria for this programme specifically targeted at two year olds  living in the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_3"&gt;Sunshine Playgroup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the children start Sunshine Playgroup, we recognise that they have already had a variety of experiences and have developed in a number of ways.  We will endeavour to build upon the learning that has taken place in the home and their immediate environment as well as previous play experiences.  Therefore the staff team will provide children with a rich variety of challenging play activities and other experiences in a stimulating environment.  The focus will be to allow children to learn at their own pace, gain a positive image of themselves as learners, be able to cope with uncertainty and to learn through trial and error.  The staff team use the &#x2018;Preschool Curricular Guidance&#x2019; document as laid down by the Department of Education to influence their planning.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="playgroup-sessions"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Monday to Friday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;9.15am to 11.45am&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;3+ years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We operate a waiting list for our creche and playgroup services.  For full information on our criteria or session fees please contact Karen Pollock on 028 7034 3259  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families</title>
      <link>/harpurs/families</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Family Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Family Visiting Service is designed to provide families with the individual support they require.  Guided by the family&#x2019;s needs we offer a listening ear, guidance, information, relevant links and contacts to enable families to realise their full potential.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through key contact visits we deliver a Sure Start programme to all babies born in the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area.  All families receive various items through a series of planned visits until the child has reached the age of two.  During this period any family, if they wish, may avail of our regular monthly support service.  These regular monthly support visits continue as long as a parent wishes until the child reaches age 4 or if the family move out of the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide information about other services and in particular services available through Coleraine Sure Start Partnership.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We facilitate a number of groups (see group information) and programmes delivered on behalf of Sure Start.  Programmes such as Nurturing, Cook-it, Infant Massage and Toddler Yoga are facilitated by ourselves and other Sure Start staff.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For further information on our family support service, contact Gretta on 028 70321620.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click here to link with Coleraine Sure Start Partnerships website.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>/harpurs/groups</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Group Support&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Tuesday Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group is for parents of children with additional needs.  It aims to provide a listening ear and help direct parents or carers to sources of relevant information as well as being a friendly, caring and supportive environment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tuesday Group at Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre runs every Tuesday, during term time from 10.00am to 11.30am.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come along and join other parents at our additional needs group.  Have a cup of tea, a chat and a laugh with staff and parents in a relaxed setting.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter who we are, there are times when it&#x2019;s good to talk!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information contact Margaret or Pauline on 028 703 21620.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Women&#x2019;s Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Women&#x2019;s Group aims to support women as parents to discuss relevant issues in a safe environment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Women&#x2019;s Group at Harpurs Hill Community Centre runs every Wednesday, during term time from 10.00am &#x2013; 12.00.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got some time on your hands?  Come along and join us... meet other mums, have a chat over a cuppa, try new activities and workshops.  What about my kids?  We offer a creche service for children aged 0 &#x2013; 4 years.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information contact Karen or Shirley on 028 703 43259.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB:&lt;/strong&gt; Creche places are limited and in high demand, therefore contact Karen or Shirley to ensure a place is available.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
