<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Harpurs Hill</title>
    <description>Harpurs Hill</description>
    <link/>
    <pubDate>2014-10-13</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>About us</title>
      <link>/harpurs/about</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;About Us&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project was established in 1993 to address low levels of preparedness for school.
It takes a holistic approach combining community development with delivering 
people-centred, family support services.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project runs an &lt;a href="/harpurs/childcare"&gt;Early Years programme&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="/harpurs/families"&gt;home visiting service&lt;/a&gt; and a range of personal development programmes and &lt;a href="/harpurs/groups"&gt;activities for adults&lt;/a&gt;.  It also encourages parents to become involved in running the Project.  The Project also shares the building with the Cuilrath Corner Nursery School which is run by the Education Service.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1999 the Project has become one of the main players in the delivery of Children&amp;#39;s Services in the Coleraine Area and in 2003 it became the lead body of the &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Coleraine Sure Start Partnership&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project is managed by a Board representing a range of stakeholders and is a company limited by guarantee.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="undertext"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre Ltd is a non-profit making, charitable organisation reliant on funding to deliver its services to the community.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Supported by&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coleraine SureStart Partnership &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Northern Health &amp;amp; Social Care Trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Department of Education &amp;amp; Early Years Organisation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Northern Childcare Partnership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aims</title>
      <link>/harpurs/aims</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;div class="box-rox cloud"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="col-md-12"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vision&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="col-md-12 text"&gt;
&#x201C;To nurture strong, resilient children and families for today, tomorrow and the future&#x201D;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="box-rox path"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="col-md-12"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mission&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="col-md-12 text"&gt;
&#x201C;We endeavour to support, strengthen and nurture children and families to achieve their full potential&#x201D;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_0"&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To nurture young children from birth through the provision of high quality care and learning environments and to ensure they reach their full potential.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To recognise and support parents in their role as primary educators of their children through home support, parenting programmes and offering high quality care and learning environments.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To empower parents to seek appropriate advice and guidance to support their families developmental needs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To signpost parents to opportunities for personal and professional development.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide parents with access to information to make informed life choices. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop an increased sense of ownership and belonging for families within their own community.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To work in partnership with all relevant children and family support agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Value base&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Empowerment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accountability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family Friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educational&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact us</title>
      <link>/harpurs/contact</link>
      <pubDate>2014-04-03</pubDate>
      <description>Contact Harpurs Hill</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>/harpurs/groups</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Group Support&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_1"&gt;Tuesday Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group is for parents of children with additional needs.  It aims to provide a listening ear and help direct parents or carers to sources of relevant information as well as being a friendly, caring and supportive environment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tuesday Group at Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre runs every Tuesday, during term time from 10.00am to 11.30am.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come along and join other parents at our additional needs group.  Have a cup of tea, a chat and a laugh with staff and parents in a relaxed setting.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter who we are, there are times when it&#x2019;s good to talk!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information contact Margaret or Pauline on 028 703 21620.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="toc_2"&gt;Women&#x2019;s Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Women&#x2019;s Group aims to support women as parents to discuss relevant issues in a safe environment.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Women&#x2019;s Group at Harpurs Hill Community Centre runs every Wednesday, during term time from 10.00am &#x2013; 12.00.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got some time on your hands?  Come along and join us... meet other mums, have a chat over a cuppa, try new activities and workshops.  What about my kids?  We offer a creche service for children aged 0 &#x2013; 4 years.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information contact Karen or Shirley on 028 7032 1620.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NB:&lt;/strong&gt; Creche places are limited and in high demand, therefore contact Karen or Shirley to ensure a place is available.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Little Rays</title>
      <link>/harpurs/childcare/little-rays</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Little Rays &#x2013; Sure Start Two to Three Year Old Development Programme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Sure Start&lt;/a&gt; programme is for two to 
three year olds is an exciting programme where the emphasis is on play and 
creativity.  We offer a variety of opportunities not only to young children but 
also to their parents and carers by actively involving them in the programme, 
thus helping to create strong relationships within our Centre. For further 
information please contact Linda Foote at Coleraine Sure Start Partnership on 
028 70321032&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criteria for this programme is specifically targeted at two year olds living in 
the &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Coleraine Sure Start&lt;/a&gt; catchment area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One to one</title>
      <link>/harpurs/families/one-to-ones</link>
      <pubDate>2014-06-21</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;One to one&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We currently connect with families who have children under 4 years of age through regular visits to the home.  We believe it is important that parents should be able to access this type of support in their own home and our Family Support Workers spend time getting to know the parent through listening, befriending, guiding and signposting to services relevant to the family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through key contact visits we deliver a &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Sure Start&lt;/a&gt; programme to all babies born in the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area. All families receive various items through a series of planned visits until the child has reached the age of four. During this period any family, if they wish, may avail of our regular monthly support service. These regular monthly support visits continue as long as a parent wishes until the child reaches age 4 or if the family move out of the Coleraine Sure Start catchment area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information on our Family Support Service, contact Gretta on 028 7032 1620.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/harpurs/families</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Family Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Family Support Team within Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre recognise  that being a parent is one of the hardest, but also one of the most rewarding, roles a person will ever undertake.  We understand that for some families friendly support and advice can make all the difference. We support parents and families on a &lt;a href="/families/one-to-ones"&gt;one-to-one&lt;/a&gt; basis in their own homes, or in &lt;a href="/groups"&gt;groups&lt;/a&gt; or through &lt;a href="/families/programmes"&gt;programmes&lt;/a&gt; and can provide access to more specialist help and support should they or their children need it.  We currently deliver our Family Support Service on behalf of the &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Coleraine Sure Start Partnership&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For further information on our family support service, contact Gretta on 028 7032 1620.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>/harpurs/childcare</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Childcare Services&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="childcare"&gt;
It is the aim of the childcare services within Harpurs Hill Children and Family Centre to provide a quality service where you and your child will feel welcomed and valued within a safe and secure environment.  We provide a variety of activities for various ages and stages of development, where children can develop and grow under the guidance of a professional, caring and fully qualified staff team.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Birth to 1 year olds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="childcare/creche"&gt;Sunshine Creche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday&lt;br&gt;
1pm to 3pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1 to 2 years olds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="childcare/creche"&gt;Sunshine Creche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wednesday &amp;amp; Thursday&lt;br&gt;
1pm to 3pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2 to 3 year olds&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="childcare/little-rays"&gt;Little Rays &#x2013; Sure Start Two to Three Year Old Development Programme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Monday - Thursday&lt;br&gt;
Session 1: 9.15am to 11.15am&lt;br&gt;
Session 2: 12.15pm - 2.15pm&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3 year olds and older&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="childcare/playgroup"&gt;Sunshine Playgroup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Monday to Friday&lt;br&gt;
9:15am to 11:45am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We operate a waiting list for our creche and playgroup services.  For full information on our criteria or session fees please contact Karen Pollock on 028 7032 1620 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmes</title>
      <link>/harpurs/families/programmes</link>
      <pubDate>2014-06-21</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Programmes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In partnership with &lt;a href="http://www.colerainesurestart.org.uk"&gt;Coleraine Sure Start Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, we offer a range of programmes.  There is something to suit everyone in those early years.  We offer Infant Massage, Toddler Yoga, Baby Swim, Cook-It and parenting programmes such as Incredible Years and Nurturing.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine Creche</title>
      <link>/harpurs/childcare/creche</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Sunshine Creche&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our creche is a great stepping stone for children progressing onto other types of childcare services.  The creche gives the children the opportunity to play and interact with other children their own age and helps build confidence and socialising skills.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="creche-sessions"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Monday &amp;amp; Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Wednesday &amp;amp; Thursday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1pm to 3pm&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Birth to 1 year&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;1 to 2 years&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact Karen on 028 7032 1620&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunshine Playgroup</title>
      <link>/harpurs/childcare/playgroup</link>
      <pubDate>2014-02-15</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;h1 id="toc_0"&gt;Sunshine Playgroup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the children start Sunshine Playgroup, we recognise that they have already had a variety of experiences and have developed in a number of ways.  We will endeavour to build upon the learning that has taken place in the home and their immediate environment as well as previous play experiences.  Therefore the staff team will provide children with a rich variety of challenging play activities and other experiences in a stimulating environment.  The focus will be to allow children to learn at their own pace, gain a positive image of themselves as learners, be able to cope with uncertainty and to learn through trial and error.  The staff team use the &#x2018;Preschool Curricular Guidance&#x2019; document as laid down by the Department of Education to influence their planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table id="playgroup-sessions"&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Sessions&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Monday to Friday&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Times&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;9.15am to 11.45am&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Age&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;3+ years&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact Karen on 028 7032 1620&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
